# **Clever Ubiagege**

MECHANICAL DESIGN ENGINEER BRENTWOOD, ESSEX
CM15 9AZ
UNITED KINGDOM
07491722771
CLEVER.UBIAGEGE@YAHOO.COM



Clever Ubiagege is an MSc educated mechanical engineer with years of experience working in the infrastructural sector of construction industry as a temporary works designer (TWD). At present he works with the infrastructural team at Peri, heavily involved in formwork design for Thames Tideway Sewage Project, bridges (abutments, piers and parapets), tunnels, retaining walls, waste treatment and power plants, as well as falsework and shoring designs. He is a member of iMeche and CIBSE, and currently working towards Chartership

Prior to working in Construction, He has been working as a mechanical design and product development engineer in the manufacturing industry.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Jul 2019 - date

# FORMWORK DESIGN ENGINEER

## **PERI Formwork and Scaffolding**

- Design formwork, falsework and shoring solutions for infrastructural projects.
- Performs and document calculations using structural design software to ensure designs are safe and economical
- Liaising with client with respect to design refinement and resolving issues pertaining to design interpretation during assembling of equipment on site
- Checking designs of Assistant formwork designers
- Good working knowledge of BS 5975 and BS EN 12812 on procedural codes and practices for temporary work designs
- Awareness of Project change/revision control and risk management processes
- Awareness of CDM regulations as well as health and safety regulations on risk assessment, ensuring that residual risks are fully noted on designs

Sept 2017 – May 2019

#### **DESIGN ENGINEER**

#### **EFCO Corp**

- Designing concrete formwork and falsework for Bridges, Stadiums, Power plants construction projects
- Creating Erection drawings and ensuring that drawing details communicate coherent and consistent information to clients.
- Liaising with client with respect to design refinement and resolving issues pertaining to design interpretation during assembling of equipment on site

• Carrying out calculations to ensure concrete pour pressure and allowable stresses are not exceeded, before submission to Senior Design Engineer for Checking.

## Jun 2016 - Jul 2017

#### RESEARCHER

# **Aalto University**

- Developed concepts for hybrid additive manufacturing (HAM) machine for production of high strength aluminium alloy
- Combine conventional Friction stir welding process and MIG welding process under certain boundary condition to attain desired result
- Documented control variables and recorded steps towards the production process which were later use to create algorithm for the HAM machine prototype
- Carried out mechanical test analysis on produced parts which include tensile and bending test, micro-indentation hardness test and micro-structural analysis.
- Compared results of mechanical properties of the test part with other Metal-based additive manufactured parts.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Aug 2015 - Jun 2017

# MSc IN MECHANICAL DESIGN ENGINEERING AND MECHATRONICS **Aalto University**

- My first year I focused on Product design and development, working alongside interdisciplinary students to provide tailored solutions on specific projects from companies within Finland.
- In my second year, the focus was on mechatronics, where we apply mechanical engineering principles, product development, Electronics and programming skills in developing concept designs for companies.

#### SKILLS

# Specific skills

- CAD software includes AutoCAD, Solidwork, Creo Parametric, Keyshot.
- Analysis software includes ANSYS Workbench, winbeam, Quickframe, MathCAD, Matlab.
- Proficient with MS Word + Excel

#### Personal qualities

- Excellent interpersonal skillS
- Good communication & listening skills
- Good problem solver
- Strong attention to detail
- Positive 'can do' approach
- Cheerful, friendly person